Radi Totev

166 Streatham Vale London **SW16 5TB**

Mobile: 07519029628

raditotev@gmail.com

GitHub

in LinkedIn

Portfolio

radi.website

I've created my first simple HTML page in 2001 as a hobby project. Later I continued experimenting with programming in my spare time by building pages using Dreamweaver or writing code in C for my Arduino projects. Since 2013 I use Ruby on Rails for building apps, RSpec and Capybara for testing, JavaScript, jQuery and Ajax for interactive effects and Bootstrap, Foundation and Sass for styling. In future I would like to learn more about and create projects with the MEAN stack.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2014 -now

Oaktree Day Nursery

Company website with admin, public and parents sections. Stack: Rails 5, Ruby 2.3, Devise, RSpec 3, Capybara, Shoulda Matchers, Factory Girl, Faker, Database Cleaner, SimpleCov, Bootstrap, Sass Rails, Font Awesome, Paperclip. PostgreSQL database and AWS S3 server for static content. https://github.com/raditotev/nursery

My Website

My personal website containing admin and public sections. There are landing, about, portfolio blog and contact pages. Stack: Rails 4.2, Ruby 2.2, Devise, RSpec 3, Capybara, Shoulda Matchers, Factory Girl, Database Cleaner, Foundation, Sass Rails , Font Awesome, Paperclip, CKEditor, Mail Form, Letter Opener, Friendly ID.

SQLite development, PostgreSQL production databases and AWS S3 server for static content.

https://github.com/raditotev/my-page

Facebook Clone

Facebook clone app, allowing users to create posts, write comments, 'like' other user's posts and send and receive friend requests. Omniauth allows users to sign in using their real Facebook account.

Stack: Rails 4.2, Ruby 2.2, Devise, Omniauth Facebook, Bootstrap, Figaro, Faker, Will Paginate, Letter Opener. SQLite development, PostgreSQL production databases https://github.com/raditotev/odin-facebook

Old Webpage

My old single page personal website. Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap https://github.com/raditotev/my-portfolio

Pomodoro Timer

Countdown app. Countdown starts with session time. When the time is over there is a bell to notify the user it's time for break. When the break time is over the user is once again notified it's time to get back to work.

Stack: HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Font Awesome, JavaScript, ¡Query, Progressbar.js

https://github.com/raditotev/pomodoro-timer

Simple Calculator

Stack: HTML, CSS, Boostrap, JavaScript, jQuery https://github.com/raditotev/js-calculator

Twitch Board

Page showing a list of Twitch streamers using Twitch's API. Online and streaming users are placed on top of the list and highlighted in green. The list can be filtered via buttons and show All, Online or Offline users only.

Stack: Boostrap, JavaScript, jQuery https://github.com/raditotev/js-calculator

Wikipedia Search

Searches Wikipedia for given query via Wikipedia's API. Returns first 10 pages. "Feeling lucky" redirects to random page.

Stack: Boostrap, JavaScript, jQuery https://github.com/raditotev/wiki-search

Weather App

Displays current weather for user's location. Data is received from open weather API.

Stack: Boostrap, JavaScript, jQuery

https://github.com/raditotev/weather-app

Random Quote Generator

Generates random quote via API callback. When the Twitter icon is clicked, Twitter's submit form is populated with the quote text, author and quote hash tags.

Stack: Boostrap, JavaScript, jQuery

https://github.com/raditotev/random-quotes

2007 - 2014

Radi Electrical Services

Director

- multiple commercial and industrial projects
- installation of lighting, power and substations
- BMS, DALI, Creston, iLight control systems

2003 - 2007

Mobimex

Web Development Project Manager

- liaising with clients and creating project specifications, meeting their needs
- organizing and assigning tasks to developers and designers
- overseeing the overall development of every project and ensuring deadlines are met
- testing each new implementation to every given project and make sure it works as supposed to

EDUCATION

2015

Udacity

Intro to Programming Nanodegree

2001-2003

Fachhochschule Deutsche Telekom, Leipzig

Telecommunications

1992-1997

School of Technology, "Electronic System Engineering at the Technical University of Sofia"

Specialist in Computer Engineering and Technologies, BTEC National Diploma

STACK

- Ruby
- Rails
- RSpec
- Capybara
- JavaScript
- jQuery
- CoffeeScript
- Bootstrap
- Foundation
- SASS
- PostgreSQL
- AWS S3

MORE INFORMATION

Languages

- English
- Bulgarian
- German

HOBBIES

- Diving
- Hiking
- Photography
- Travelling
- Reading

Electronics